Guide to the Gordon Bower papers SC1223
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Gordon Bower papers
1950-2014
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Bower, Gordon H.
SC1223
23.75 Linear Feet 16 boxes and 6.32 GB of digital files
Access to Collection
Recommendations and student materials are closed for 75 years from date of creation. Otherwise tThe materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given by Gordon Bower to Stanford University, Special Collections in October 2014.
Biographical / Historical
Gordon Bower is the Albert Ray Lang Professor (Emeritus) of Psychology at Stanford University. He received a BA from Case Western Reserve University in 1954, and an MS (1957) & Ph.D. (1959) in from Yale University, both in Psychology. Bower’s research interests include the study of human memory, mnemonic devices, retrieval strategies, recording strategies, and category learning, including cognitive processes, emotion, imagery, language and reading comprehension as they relate to memory.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists primarily of teaching files and research files, correspondence, as well as files from professional organizations. Also included are student materials and recommendations, both of which are restricted for 75 years from date of creation.
Bower, Gordon H.; Bower, Gordon H.; Stanford University. Department of Psychology. Faculty; Bower, Gordon H.; Stanford University. Department of Psychology. Faculty
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2015-017
  - Psych 103: Conditioning Learning, 1960-1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Notes P 264, Seminar on Learning (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bower: models, lecturer notes on Mathematical Models, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - G. Bower: Beh. Mod. Seminar notes "Beh. Mod in applied settings", 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bower's notes as a Speed Reading Student, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Psych 101A Conditioning learning, 1959-1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ideas for Experiments (+ some math models) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Psychological Conceptions of Man 142, Taught at Stanford-in-Vienna, Austria Fall Quarter it was conducted according to the procedures specified as "Personalized System of Instruction" (PSI), 1970 Fall (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Psych 264 Seminar some math modelling, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Math model class: Estes' Stimulus sampling theory, and the pattern models (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - notes on math models when Bower was a Yale graduate student, 1956-1959 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Psych 210 memory notes of G. Bower (+R.C. Atkinson, Co-teacher). Also notes on serial learning (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Psych 210: Human Cognitive Psychology, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Psych 210 Learning Theory, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Math models classes, 1961-1968 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Yale seminar with F. Logan VTE model for peripheral scaling, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Math models course notes (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Psych 210 Memory Winter Quarter, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Class notes of classes that Gordon was auditing, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Psy 264 Coding Theory Topics. G. Bower (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Psych 210 Gordon Bower, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Psych 264 Winter Quarter, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Psych 264 notes Learning Bower, 1975 Spring (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Yale idea notes mainly "rat experiments", 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Notes of GB's attending Yale classes, 1956-1958 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Psych 264 Topics in Human Learning Gordon Bower, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Psych 264 Human learning, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Psych 264, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Psych 264 Anderson's "Atomic Components of Thought" seminar notes co-taught by Bower and Anderson, 1999 Winter (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "A logical explication of the concept of measurement" Gordon Bower term paper written for a psych class at Western Reserve University, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Psych 264, 1992 Winter (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Psych 165 Survey of Mathematical Psychology, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Misc. notes: ideas for experiments some notes on my readings (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Frosh seminar stuff, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "Explorations in Human Memory, 2003-2004 Winter (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Frosh: syllabus preview handouts (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Frosh seminar, 2001-2003 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Frosh: second meeting (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Frosh: 3rd meeting (Chapters 3 4) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Frosh: 4th meeting (distortions) (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Frosh: 5th meeting (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - meeting #6: implicit memory (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Frosh: meeting #7 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Frosh: meeting #8 psychogenic amnesia (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Frosh: meeting #9 the memory wars (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Frosh meeting #10 Elders (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Gratitude testimonials Psych 15N (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Gratitude testimonials, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - misc (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Class 5: Implicit measures of attitudes (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - STFD Cog Clin, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Xerox copies of papers read by class (Cog. Clinical course) (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Expts. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - "The Psychotherapist's Guide to Human Memory" Janet L. jones (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Day 1: Stfd: Cog Clinical University of Texas, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Day 2: Infant Memory (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - STFD #1, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Mem. Notes, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Session 3: Acc. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Stfd: Emotion psych 267 learning (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Memory distertions (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Ses. 4 Autobiography biases (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Repression recovery of CSA (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - False memory (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - notes (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Implicit (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - notes (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Depression research papers (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Behavior Research Paper (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Anxiety Disorder Papers (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Brid Cring Canyon (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Bridging the Canyon session 10 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Basic Behavioral Science Research for Mental Health (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Tricks for the Memory. G. Bower (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Temporal spatial distance in situation models (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - cognitive science speech, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - commencement speech, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Bob Sternberg: PACE opening ceremony, 2001 Feb 19 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - APA intro #1 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Farewell Tenenbaum, 2001 Dec 18 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Library "bound" Bower reprints (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - paper, 1979 Aug 29 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - paper, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Cornell University speech on "imagery memory", 1972 Mar (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Simple storage models for immediate memory: a working paper, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - on understanding actions in narratives - invited Address, 1985 Sep 6 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - biography of Bower, 1979 Aug 29 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - intro. Math matlab - folder #1, 1968 Autumn (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Psych 265c notes (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - paper, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Droodles (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Gordon Bower paper, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Major Area Paper Gordon Bower, 1958 Mar 20 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Psych 265c models, 1967 Spring (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Mental imagery and memory, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Talks to non-psychologists ("popular") lecture to Stanford staff at management training (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - unpublished working paper on concept identification mold, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Immunological conditioning in Mice (pilot data) - GB and Leu Eptein worked on this, 1984 Feb 23 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - The Organization of Recall, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Talk to EPS Gordon Bower (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - WPA stuff, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Closing remarks at Retirement Party of Psychology department, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - NIMH/APA #1 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - GHB dissertation speech, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - APA Hyman intro, 2000 Aug 4 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Emotion talk to Cowell, Trustees computer science students (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - notes from NIA remark (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - papers (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - word association exp. (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Events exp. (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - prediction exp. (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - thirst exp. (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Brussels speech (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - to be submitted, 1992 Feb 12 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - owens and Dafoe materials (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence University of Texas, 1968 Feb 7 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - APA talk PAL, 1960 Sep 5 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Queueing models for attention (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Princeton paper - in press (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Psychology 210, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - HAM talk Psych faculty talk, 1974 Apr 10 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Psychology talk UC talk, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Idea book of Gordon Bower Yale Grad school, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - "Idea book" of Gordon Bower at Yale University while in school, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Public talks on the model, 1961 Jan 25 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Skinnr - Bar work of GB, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Application for research grant, 1962 Dec 8 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Air force/ Grant proposal, 1986 Oct 21 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Memory for facts figures (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - psychology issues (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - "80th Birthday Party" remarks, 2014 May 24 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - getting grants (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Miller APA talk (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Seligman introduction WPA, 2004 Apr (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Ed Smith G's talk, 1967 November (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - APS opening ceremony #1, 1993 Jun 25 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - news magazine symposium #1, 1993 Jun 25 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - intro's AOA: E.O. Wilson Al Wagner, 1999 Aug (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - introduction Frands de Wal, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Maxine Aiken's Retirement party speech, 1981 Jun 10 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - G's speech to his staff (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - remarks at Memorial service`, 2002 Mar 24 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Celia's retirement speech (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Annie E., `2003 May 20 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Models talk at Texas (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Do's and Don'ts for speeches (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - All Stanford grants (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Talk on NIMH Task forces, 1993 Jan 11 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - NIMH slides from Molly (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Endowed chair funds Sabbatical leave accumulation (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Bower- Wessells agreements RE deaning, 1992 Feb 15 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Rockefeller: talk correspondence, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Research notes (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - journal (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - G. Bower journal (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Bower journal, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - journal (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Seminar: behav. Mod. In app. Setting. Rm 100 -- Gordon H. Bower (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Quiz 5 -- Behavior modification (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Behavior modification quiz #6 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Behavior modification quiz 7 handout, 1977 November 17 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Quiz grades, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Seminar: Behavior modification in Applied Settings (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Behavior modification Quiz #7, 1976 November 18 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Seminar quizes, 1975-1978 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Behavior modification Quiz #1, 1978 Fall (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Behavior modification quiz #2, 1978 Fall (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Seminar for Entering Students, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Behavior modification quiz #3, 1978 Fall (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Behavior Modification quiz #4, 1978 Fall (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Behavior modification quiz #5, 1978 Fall (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Behavior modification quiz #6, 1978 Fall (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Behavior modification quiz #7, 1978 Fall (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Behavior modification quiz #8, 1978 Fall (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Behavior modification quiz #8, 1978 Fall (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Extra make- up quiz Gordon Bower Beh. Mod., 1976 November 23 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Seminar for Entering Students (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Psychology in the real world; quiz 1 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Beh. Mod project papers, 1977 Fall (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Syllabi (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Slides Cog. Sci funny talk, extra mental models talks (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - outline (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Categorization Symposiums (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - papers (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Japan cog. Sci talk, 1980 Sep 9-15 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - the information processing approach, 1983 Oct 3 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - APA talks, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Gordon's retirement from chairmanship speech, 1982 Jun 5 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - hilgard speech notes, 1983 Dec (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Cohen, Jonathan Cognitive Search, 2002 November 22 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Ellen Markman retirement from psychology chair, 1997 Jun 12 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - The Actual Zuibardo Speech, 2003 November 1 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Estes Festshrift - Harvard, 1989 Sep 16 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Norm Wessells Mark Farewell, 1988 Jun (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Memorial Service for Neal Edgar Miller, 2002 Mar 23 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Roger Shepard Retirement Dinner / Toast by GB, 1996 Jan 13 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - 75th Birthday, 2007 November 17 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Talk to prospective grad students (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - talk to 1st year students, 2006 May 12 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Santa Clara talk to undergrad psych (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Fri Boorg speech copy 2 overheads (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - notes for my Luwan memory course (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Fribourg speech/ story understanding (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Padua T. K. (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Materials for San Francisco alumni talk (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Miller party (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - #2 Aps opening ceremony, 1993 Jun 25 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Hilgard Symposium #1: Sunday APA, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - PTSD: copy 1 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Herb Simon intro (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Slides (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Anderson 1 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Tony's Wedding (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Conference #1 Mischel, 2005 Jun 11 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Wedding talk Julia's, 1997 Sep 23 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Talk to CMU grad students, 1983 Mar (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - WPA speech, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Santa Barbara talk on Person Memory (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Laura Cartensen speech at her retirement from psych chairmanship, 2006 Jun 15 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - San Marcos talk (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Arrowhead talk, 1974 Jun (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - 6. Mental imagery and associative learning - Carnegie Mellon, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - negatives for figures for NY Academic Science Talk Princeton, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - 4. Psychology 193, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Syllabus, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Improving recall by retrieval cues that aggregate interfering material Bower Speech (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Trari Mann exp. Talk (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Possible research ideas (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Research notes ideas for talk at AABT convention (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Program of 2nd Stanford - UC Berkely student (Cognitive) Convention, 1980 May 17 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Possible experiments (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - unlabeled, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Recall of Person Information - Sillogan Bower, 1980 May 2 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Princeton psych department review, 1992 Jun (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - New York University: Self study report, 1993 Oct (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Case Western Reserve Review, 1998 Mar - Apr (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - 1 of G's grant proposals notes for his Schema talk at Japan - US cognitive psychology conference in Tokyo, 1980 Sep (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - A - C, 1987-1998 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - D - I, 1984-1988 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - J - M, 1984-2001 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - N - Q, 1986-2000 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - R - U, 1983-2000 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - V - Z, 1984-1989 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - ERL retirement roast, 2000 Jun 10 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - PhDs that GB was 1st or reader on disertation (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Psychonomics Society speech Bower (overheads), 1991 November (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - NIMH talk: Athens, Greece, 1995 Jul 6 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - APA / NIMH symposium MTF, 1995 Aug 12 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Gluck Config cue (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Speech: aging memory Poc. Grad school of Psych, 1991 Jun 2 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Federation speech copy #1, 1991 Apr (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Anthony D. Wagner (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - G. Bower paper, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Elab Act in paired Assoc. learning. Berkeley, 1986 Fall (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - La Jolla paper (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Psych 207 speech, 1977 Oct (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - 6.7 travel lecture notes short term memory, 1968 Fall (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Arrowhead conference handouts, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Talks in 1971 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Possible questions, 2009 Mar 6 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Grant application, 1995 May 19 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Psych 264 notes, 1992 Jan (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - American Psych Association, 1990 Dec 18 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Config. Cue lecture: Vals (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Talk to psych 207, 1978 Oct 19 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Psych 207 talk, 1991 Oct (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - FSU speech (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Speech notes, Mental models FSU. Hong Kong on "Reading", 1998 Jun 17 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Gilligan: first year project (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Psych 264 - lectures on correlated reward and micromolar theory, 1968 spring (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Lecture #2 overview of cognitive system (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Psych 103 Animal lab: all notes (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Association Model for free recall, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Do's and don'ts for research talks (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - You've come a long way, baby! (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - 193. Seminar in Theory and Quantitative Methods, 1959 - 1960 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - speech to NIMH Advisory Board re our study of night programs, 1993 May 13 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - half year plan, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Gordons victram trip/bookings (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Qeueing with Interference and Limited Span, 1964 summer (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Harvard Speech, 1997 Mar 19 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Emotion Soc Percept: Vals talk/Switzerland Copy #2 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - SUPA talk, 1991 Fall (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Mann v Thompson papers Speech Notes (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Reno: Priming Talk, 1995 November 3 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Psych 196 lecture for Ewart Thomas like Adv. Intro psych class (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - STFD: infant memory, 2002-2003 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Trauma memory, 2004-2005 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - papers on repressed memory, 2003-2005 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Papers on suppressed memories of abuse, 1984-2001 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Hypnosis and Memory, 1989-2003 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Psychology 210: Social personal biases in memory, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Psych 267 papers, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Influence of mood on recall, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - GB's summary replies to questions about his career, 1982-1993 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - the social cognitive process - Mischel, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Papers on multiple personalitydisorders, 1995-2005 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Psychology of Life stories, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper clippings - Child Sexual Abuse, 1985-1995 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Aging and Memory (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Continuing Studies speech, 2005 Oct (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Kentucky notes - UBC, Yale, NYU emotion and social cognition, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Math psych 215, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - "Dittos" for psych 165 final exam, 1974 Autumn (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Psychology 165 - lecture notes, 1974 Winter (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Psychology 165 homework, 1974 Fall (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - UT Dallas talk, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Seminar - psych 264, 1975 Spring (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Coding in Short term memory - Psych 210 lectures, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Public talks on Human Associative Memory (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Reward model (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Handouts - Psych 223 (Bower and Ed Smith), 1979 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Undergraduate talk re Graduate Study in Psychology, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Psychology 264 - topics in human learning, 1981-1982 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Psych 264 - syllabus, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Psych 264 - seminar, 1989 Spring (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Psych 210 - Lecture notes (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Psychology of trauma, 2000 Winter (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Math Learning theory seminar, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Psych 264 syllabus, 1999 Winter (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Awards for distinguished scientific contributions, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Psych 264 - schedule, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Intro Psych lecture, 1995 Winter (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - overhead notes - psych 210 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Memory and remembering - rough draft, 1980 winter (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - General discussion of memory (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Historical introduction to learning memory (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Classical conditioning (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Instrumental conditioning (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Acquisition of memories (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Inductive learning (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Cognitive Motor skills (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Working memory (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Short- term memory (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Transient Memories (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Transfer of info to long term memory (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Learning techniques Mnemonics (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Retrieval Measures (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Retention of memories (Anderson text - 2nd edition) (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Forgetting and Interference (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Priming and Implicit Memory (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Skill learning (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Frequency, recency, and metamemory (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Emotion and memory (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Categories and Category learning (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Semantic memory (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Memory for sentences (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Memory for texts and stories (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Psychology 210 papers (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Learning how to learn (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Psych 210 lecture notes, 1999-2001 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Cognitive clinical CDs, 2003-2005 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - G's CS lecture, 2004 May 13 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Employment, grants, etc (Bower) job offers in early 1960's (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Zimbardo Retirement, 2003 November 1 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - APS interview, 2009 May 13 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Experiments in Story Comprehension, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Education: reading math (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Neuropsychology of memory (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Autobiographic memory (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - memory for places and people (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Social and Personal biases in Memory (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Dissociation in memory: functional amnesia (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Midterms (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Finals, 1989-1999 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Relevant readings Psych 264, 2000 Winter (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Psych 264 Seminar some math modelling, 1993 Spring (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Focus renewal proposal (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Mood memory experiments commentaries, 1985 Sep 8 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Iowa -- IDA BEAM lecture, 1987 Jul (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - on Understanding Actions in narratives, 1985 Sep 6 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Papers, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Federation paper, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Japan: emotion social, 2001 November 8 (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - Conf. cue notes: copy #1 (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - Cog sci general talk at North Carolina State, 1989 May 5 (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - Prototype learning speech, 1986 Mar 19-21 (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Miscellaneous notes to keep (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - Satanic abuse, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - PBS: Forgetting Alzheimers, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)
  - Divided memories part 1, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 10)